Lee and Mary Grimes Travel Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Lee and Mary Grimes Travel Slide Collection
1960-1990
VRC 105
Yale University Arts Library
5.83
14 boxes
3,151 35 mm travel slides taken on tours in various countries worldwide. The photos are largely standard views of familiar subjects. The photos of local culture also seem to be standard views (i.e. the Indian snake charmer).
Grimes, Lee, 1920-
Grimes, Mary Cochran
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
3,151 35 mm travel slides taken on tours in various countries worldwide. The photos are largely standard views of familiar subjects. The photos of local culture also seem to be standard views (i.e. the Indian snake charmer).
Arrangement
By country or tour
Travel photography; Slides
- France, 1958, 1962, 1965, and 1967 [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
  General
  France, 1958, 1962, 1965, and 1967 Locations including Mont S. Michel, Avignon, Versailles (purchased slides), various chateaux, S. Emilion, Bordeaux, Rheims, Lascaux (faded slides) and other locations in Perigord, Paris, Andorra. Also included are photos of personal interest only. Most photos are of standard tourist views. (159 slides)
- France, 1967 [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
  Locations including Angers, Fontainebleau, various chateaux, Carnac, Quimper, Chinon, Tregastel, Caen, Bayeux, Dinan, Rouen, Mont S. Michel, Falaise, Avranches, Fougeres, Vitre, Honfleur, Deauville, Amboise, Villandry, Azay-le-Rideau, and Langeais. (263 slides)
- France, 1992 [Slide box 3] (Box 2)
  Locations include Nice, Paris, Cannes, the Riviera, Monaco, Rheims, Perigeuex, Carcassone, Fontainebleau, Nantes, Angers, Chinon, Biot, S. Paul-de-Vence, Antibes, Rocamadour, Carnac, Monte Carlo, and Menton. 24 slides are included that were purchased from the Musee National Fernand Leger in Biot and the Musee Picasso in Antibes. Entertainingly, there is a slide marked "Redhead, Monaco, 1958" of a nude woman posing in classic pin-up style, and almost every slide of the beach in Cannes includes topless young women. (231 slides)
- Spain, ca. 1965 [Slide box 4] (Box 2)
  Locations including Madrid, Segovia, Valley of the Fallen, Seville, the Alhambra, Toledo, the Escorial, Cordoba, Torremolines, and Carmona. (195 slides)
- Scotland, England, Belgium Germany, Austria, Italy, Monaco, Geneva, Holland, Denmark, ca. 1958 [Slide box 5] (Box 3)
  Locations include Edinburgh, Pittenweem, Sterling Castle (Scotland), London, Oxford, Arundel Castle, Stratford, Warwick Castle, Gloucester, Bath, Stonehenge, Salisbury, Winchester, Heidelberg, the Rhine, Brussels Fair, Venice, Portofino, Rome, Florence, Vienna, Salzburg, Munich, Geneva, Amsterdam, Fredensborg, Copenhagen, Abbotsford, Kronburg, Tivoli, and Pisa. (262 slides, many badly faded)
- Japan, 1968 [Slide box 6] (Box 3)
  Locations include Tokyo, Nikko, Kyoto, Kamakura, Huryuji, Yokosuka, Toshoan, Tosmofu, and Nara. Most are of shrines and temples with some shots of people. 50 slides are purchased from a Japanese vendor, and are very faded. (222 slides)
- Bangkok, Angkor, Hong Kong, 1968 [Slide box 7] (Box 4)
  Locations include Bangkok, with scenes of local culture as well as historic sites, Nakurn Pathom, Angkor Wat, and Hong Kong (mostly views of scenery). (190 slides)
- Kabul, Peshawar, Lahore, Srinagar, Delhi, Udaipur, Jaipur, Agra, 1968 [Slide box 8] (Box 4)
  Locations include Istalif, Kabul, Srinagar, Lahore, Peshawar, Delhi, Jaipur, Udaipur, and Agra. Many are scenes of local culture, with the rest of historic sites. (233 slides)
- Varanasi, Nepal, Calcutta, Madras, Ceylon, Singapore, Johore, Kuala Lumpur, 1968 [Slide box 9] (Box 5)
  Locations include Kathmandu, Varanasi, Mahabalipuram, Madras area, Calcutta, Patan (Nepal), Dambulla (Ceylon), Pulunnarum, Anuradhapura, Columbo, Kandy, Kuala Lumpur, Johore, Singapore. Many are scenes of local culture, with the rest of historic sites. (253 slides)
- Damascus, Palmyra, Turkey [Slide box 10] (Box 5)
  Locations include Priene, Miletus, Didyma, Ephesus, Pergamum, Bergama, Palmyra, Damascus, Istanbul. Most are of historic sites, with several of local scenery. (145 slides)
- Lisbon, Athens, Crete, Lebanon, Iran, Iraq, 1966-1968 [Slide box 11] (Box 6)
  Locations include Athens (mostly the Acropolos), Herakleion, Knossos, Beirut, Baalbeck Arba, Baghdad, Ctesiphon, Lisbon, Tripoli, Teheran, Persepolis, Shiraz, Isfahan, Phaistus, Gortus, and Byblos. Scenes of historic sites and local culture, along with some of personal interest only (Mary Grimes at the hotel pool). (276 slides)
- Morocco, 1987 [Slide box 12] (Box 6)
  Locations include Tangier, Chelah, Mernqi, Ziz river valley, Marrakesh, Rissani, Lixus, Sale, Rabat, Mernes, Volubilis, Atlas Mountains, Fez, Ksar, and Casablanca. Scenes of historic sites and local culture, along with some of personal interest only. (232 slides)
- Egypt, 1991 [Slide box 13] (Box 7)
  Locations include Edfu, Abu Simbel, Beni Hassan, views of the Nile, views of the pyramids, Philae, Luxur, Karnak, Abydus, Dendera, Thebes, Cairo, Hermopolis, Jaggara, Kum Ombo, Aswan Quarry, and Saqqara. Scenes of historic sites and local culture, along with some of personal interest only. Slide box also contains a multi-page list of slides as organized for a slide show. The writing is largely illegible. (196 slides)
- Mexico, ca. 1960-1964 [Slide box 14] (Box 7)
  Locations include Xochimilco, University City, Tepexpan, Teotihuacan, Mexico City, Oaxaca, Guadalajara, Mazatlan, Taxco, Cuernavaca, Mazatlan, Monte Alban, and bullfight photos. Slide box is marked as "Trip with Talley, 1960" and "Family Trip, 1964." Scenes of historic sites and local culture, along with some of personal interest only. (294 slides)